uh
[Music]
do
hello good evening good day everybody
hope you're doing well and welcome to
the ask with the show episode
today we discuss geopolitics history
current affairs and so on
uh and as always before we get into it
let me see who all is there with us and
greet you all i can see animesh
bonfire raj
aryan raj veer
arman
and lots of other people good evening
good day to all of you great to see you
all
and with that said let us get into the
questions for tonight
and what is question number one
question number one is uh multiple
questions that i've received about this
particular issue michonne says what are
your views on china threatening nancy
pelosi that they will shoot down her
aircraft if she visits taiwan
and the rohit says china threatened the
us over nancy pelosi's visit to taiwan
do you think a small conflict can happen
republicans also support the biden
government on this issue yeah
so what's happening is that nancy pelosi
is right now as we speak on her way to
asia maybe she must have already reached
some place in asia
so she's on a tour of i believe several
asian destinations several asian nations
and
uh a visit to taiwan was planned it was
on the card so i'm not sure if it's if
she's still going ahead with that but uh
the indications were there it was
announced that she would visit the
island of taiwan and that uh
brought forth a very strong uh
response from china
they said that the u.s is undermining
the so-called one china policy that the
two nations have agreed to
and it
the chinese are saying it's a red line
that we cannot allow anyone to cross if
this happens then there will be
consequences very severe very strong
consequences essentially they are
threatening war they even went to the
extent of saying that if nancy pelosi
reaches taiwan they could even shoot her
plane down and any other aircraft
fighter etcetera that are accompanying
her
and they have been conducting live
firing exercises in the straight um in
the region near taiwan of the chinese
coast
they are massing uh
military equipment
personnel vehicles etc
uh close to the taiwan uh straight etc
so and and
they have been
upping the ante when it comes to their
incursions into taiwan into so called
taiwanese airspace and all that
so the chinese have made it extremely
clear in public repeatedly that this is
a red line that the u.s cannot cross if
the u.s crosses this red line then china
will essentially go to war they will
shoot they will possibly shoot down the
aircraft of nancy pelosi any other
accompanying aircraft and that
essentially is an act of war if you do
that
so
they have staked
their credibility on this issue
right
the thing is this
the chinese communist party
cannot afford
to be seen as weak in front of their own
population their own public mr xi
jinping cannot afford to be seen as weak
and and conciliatory to the us
because their entire plan their entire
basis for legitimacy is that
is is nationalism that china is going to
rise and that is the that is the
trade-off for the chinese public that
you accept our hegemony you accept our
dictatorship our one party role our
imperial rule over or the chinese public
in exchange for us making china a great
nation again
that is the
well unsaid unspoken contract
and therefore the chinese communist
party and mr xi jinping cannot under any
circumstances
afford
to appear weak
in front of the republic yeah and we
know that various american officials
have been routinely visiting taiwan yeah
uh generals military personnel etc but
nancy pelosi is a very high-ranking
u.s government official so that is a
whole different uh ball game when it
comes to her visit to taiwan
so um they have made it very clear they
would essentially go to war
and
shoot down the aircraft if the if nancy
pelosi is to visit
so the question now is
what is nancy pelosi going to do she
would have reached some part of asia by
now i suppose yeah
will she go ahead with the taiwan visit
it looks like she is kind of backing
down from that the us government seems
to be backing down from that
um maybe it was just
a way for the us to test how far the
chinese are willing to go
and they have gorged the response
and most likely i would say that
nancy pelosi may not go ahead with this
visit to taiwan
the u.s doesn't need to escalate this
matter further
they have things pretty much under
control taiwan is essentially under
their control they have the island chain
the first island chain second island
chain they own the us owns japan right
japan is the us colony south korea is a
u.s colony then you have guam
in the in the south pacific region which
is which is another island that's under
u.s control it's a major
naval and uh
air force base
australia also is under u.s control it's
the u.s colony they have 15 000 troops
permanently stationed there on a
rotation basis the americans on
australian soil and so on
so um they don't need to push china too
far
but
if they back down if the americas back
down which i think they would be likely
to do then it would what will be the
consequence of that that would be
definitely a loss of a certain amount of
prestige for the americans right that
they blinked first
that they uh
that they caved in to chinese threats
that is certainly going to be a certain
amount of loss of prestige and loss of
credibility which is more important
prestigious okay but credibility is more
important the us is the guarantor of
security
of security to south korea to japan
to australia to taiwan
and if the us
falls back
under threats then uh nations like south
korea nations like japan even nations
like australia will ask some very hard
questions to themselves that can we
trust the americans when it comes to
defending us
because that's the that's the deal right
the us is going
the u.s guarantees the national security
of taiwan and south korea and japan and
even australia and new zealand
so now these nations will ask them some
very hard questions if the u.s backs
down from this
visit to taiwan
and as we can see these are all
indications of the fact that the us
dominance and hegemony in the world is
slowly slowly step by step inch by inch
eroding away
yeah 20 years ago the americans would
not have given in to chinese threats
it it the
would not have been conceivable 20 years
ago but today
especially at least in this region the
americans would
are most likely to step back
so that's what i think will happen it's
something that's in progress right now i
most likely think that nancy pelosi will
most likely not visit taiwan if she does
visit taiwan there could be a
significant escalation once the first
shots are fired you'd never know up to
what extent
things can escalate and i don't think
the americans want that the thing is
are the chinese actually willing to go
to war
is it i mean they will obviously have
done a risk
cost benefit analysis risk analysis can
they afford to go to war with the us
over this all this matter
the chinese economy is is intricately
tied to the american economy china is
not a resource independent nation
china depends on
energy security from from the from the
gulf region yes when the partial russian
gulf and and so on there are various
choke points the malacca choke point the
hormuz
this uh strait of hormuz and so on which
can be choked off
by the americans even by certain other
nations which may be in that region yeah
as we know
uh
china would would suffer significantly
under u.s sanctions that the americans
sanction china
china imports
i think millions of tons of protein from
the us you know meat
i think their entire pro protein
they depend on on american meat for
their protein needs china and and much
more
so uh china is a nation that is
liable to suffer significantly
if the americans decide to impose
sanctions on them so the americans may
not even have to go to war with china if
the chinese do such an action they may
just
impose sanctions in china all kinds of
sanctions the way they have done on the
on the russians
and then russia is doing well
china won't do that well so there are
all these things to consider and
considering all that i think even the
chinese may be bluffing to some extent
but they can't afford to bluff
too far because the chinese public will
then stop supporting the ccp and mr xi
jinping when they can't afford to have
that happen
so
most likely considering all these things
i think nancy pelosi is unlikely to
visit taiwan the americans will most
likely back off from this and that will
be that will be seen as a loss of
loss of prestige and
people will slowly
lose confidence in the us ability to
defend nations from chinese uh
uh chinese bullying and threats so yeah
that's what i think is the situation
let's see late let's wait a notch watch
uh you never know how things are gonna
be but uh that's what i think will most
likely happen
okay question number two raghav says
okay this question again
i think i answered this question every
week don't they
russia is not russia is failing in
ukraine russia has not done anything
russia is
uh and so on so forth so let's
so let's pretend this is another
question
i wish somebody would ask me the
a different question
what are the lessons
from the ukraine war
especially for a nation like india i'm
not going to answer this question this
is a question i answer every single week
i'm not gonna repeat myself over and
over again
let's imagine that the question was what
are the lessons from for india
from the ukraine war from the ukraine
conflict because the conflict began in
in february 24 february i believe this
year 2022 it's almost august yeah five
months or so
and
now we have sufficient information
sufficient data to draw some lessons
from this conflict right
so what are the lessons for india from
the ukraine conflict because every
nation every major nation is watching
this uh war this conflict very closely
and
learning and drawing inferences and
lessons from what's happening there so
what are the lessons first of all
witness how russia has been able to
withstand american sanctions
why has russia been able to withstand
u.s sanctions and why is russia doing
remarkably well the economy is doing
just fine yeah
uh the ruble is the strongest currency
most likely in the whole world right now
the ruble has appreciated against the us
dollar the ruble has gone even even
further ahead than what it where it was
in february right
so
the reason
why the russian economy has not been
destroyed
on the other hand it's doing well why is
it so it's because russia is essentially
an otarki what's an atari a nation
that's self-sufficient in most major
resources
agriculture russia has is
self-sufficient in agriculture in food
resources it doesn't need to import food
products grains etc from anywhere it
produces all the food it needs that's
number one secondly
russia is has energy self-sufficiency
russia doesn't need to import
oil gas or whatever else from anywhere
else
russia is able to produce all of that on
its own soil on its own territory so
russia has energy security it's the
energy security is assured
thirdly
um so that's number one
there is energy security and then there
is agriculture then there are things
like russia has a strong industrial base
uh it's one of the major producers of
things like cement
steel
and things like that
and these are the real foundations of a
nation's gdp if you look at the various
gdps of the world you can see china is
so far ahead u.s is so far ahead but a
lot of the calculations that go into
these these gdp numbers
depend on
well
services and goods that don't really
produce anything
you know
the real measure of a nation's gdp is is
agriculture
energy
uh industrial output
uh
steel
cement all the things essentially the
things that went into the calculations
of gdp
numbers in the 1920s and 1930s that's
what really matters
if you are self-sufficient in those
metrics
then nobody can destroy your nation or
your economy yeah
and so that's what's happening russia is
doing very well these sanctions have not
worked
it's it's russia is essentially
untouched and then they have been able
to link their they have decided to link
their currency to gold to the to the
price of gold because they have
sufficient reserves of gold right
so that is also something that's worked
in the favor and that's why the russian
ruble is doing so well because it
essentially is a proxy for actual gold
right
you're guaranteed to get get gold in
exchange for rubles if you ask for it so
that's the reason why the russians are
doing well so that is the economic thing
so does india have these
these security measures are we
self-sufficient is india's self-social
sufficient in from the from the terms of
from the perspective of food security
agriculture i think india imports
much i mean not all
not a great deal but a significant
amount of
its
food grains etc are imported from other
places mainly from maybe from africa
from other places so that is something
that india should look into food
security
energy security india needs to india is
dependent on the gulf nations mostly for
energy security
so in case you are dependent on other
nations you need to have strategic
reserves
that
can last for months not weeks yeah
it's not enough to have strategic oil
reserves that will last you for three
weeks or four weeks you need to have
strategic reserves that will last you
for 12 months the whole nation you need
to build that capacity so that's another
lesson indian is to learn
and uh
industry is important all these things
india has to look into now when it comes
to the military
factor
these are the economic factors that
we've discussed what about the military
well there are lots of lessons to learn
from the
war from from the military perspective
first of all you need lots and lots of
missiles 50 missiles 100 missiles 200
missiles is simply not enough
thus far in the past four five six
months five months the russians have
used up more than three thousand four
thousand cruise missiles
that's a huge number of missiles and
they still have lots more
this is a war that's dragging on they it
is dragging on on purpose the russians
want it to drag on
right they could have taken over ukraine
and smashed the flat in the play the
place in three weeks if they wanted but
they have chosen to fight a certain kind
of war
and there must be a good reason for that
and they have they have
fired more than 3 000 missiles by now
cruise missiles and not just one kind of
missile multiple types of missiles with
different ranges and different uh
purposes right india has a one-trick
pony the brahmos missile of course we
have different kinds of brahmos missiles
we have a 290 kilometer range a 700
kilometer range and allegedly other
ranges as well and we now have different
variants of the brahmos also you know
the brahmos ng which may or may not be
developed i don't know what the
situation is but india needs to have a
significantly large stock of cruise
missiles and not just one type of
missile multiple types of missiles india
needs to get its act together the nearby
missile needs to be developed other
variants need to be developed
and you need numbers quantity has a
quality of its own you need thousands of
missiles in your in your stock you need
to have a stock of thousands of missiles
not just a couple of hundred pesos
that's not said that is simply not
enough you need
enormous amounts of arms and ammunition
in reserve
enough to last you several months not
enough not just for two weeks
you need
enormous stocks of ammunition
bullets
shells artillery shells you need large
number of artillery guns right we we are
still depending on the 1980s bow force
guns as far as i know we need more we
need lots and lots of those howitzers so
and other artillery uh weapons
so the lessons of the russian war are
very clear you need numbers quantity is
very important and then you need to
invest in something like the multiple
mlrs rocket system right
let me show you what that looks like
what does that look like
what is mlrs this is what mlrs looks
like so this is
these are various mlrs systems
you need to be able to fire enormous
salvos of these rockets
multiple launch rocket system mlrs
india has its own pinaka system we need
large numbers of these because these are
extremely extremely useful extremely
handy
this is when you when you launch
enormous numbers of rockets in one go in
in salvos
that is is a game changer when it comes
to artillery warfare and you know
any kind of war you also need drones
drones have been a game changer in this
war
not just for recognitions and detection
purposes but also for firing missiles
from the sky undetected you need various
kinds of drones drones that can loiter
for hours and observe with with high
precision what's happening on the ground
without being detected
and also drones that can fire missiles
on on ground targets or that can
pinpoint the location of moving ground
targets so that they can be fired upon
using mlrs or various other
weapons you need these things you need
kamikaze drones suicide drones drones
that will destroy themselves and destroy
the target you need all of this this is
the 21st century you cannot go into
warfare with the 20th century mindset so
these are some of the lessons india
needs to learn urgently
from the ukraine conflict
right so that is the question i was
hoping somebody would ask but anyway
i've answered it
says a cricketer destroyed pakistan
which is already in disarray and a
comedian actor is destroying the entire
ukraine
well yes and no
the cricketer mr khan mr imran khan was
never really in power he was prime
minister only in name we know who really
runs the country they always need some
puppet some figurehead to put in front
of the public so that the people can
blame that person so imran khan decided
to be that person imran khan was never
in power he never had any
decision-making uh ability
the real decisions were always being
made by the pakistan army and even today
whoever isn't is the prime minister
today i think it is shabbat siri sharif
it doesn't matter who is the prime
minister of pakistan the prime minister
is a puppet
okay so he doesn't matter he
or he or she doesn't matter the
pakistani prime minister has no real
power whatsoever so mr imran khan did
not destroy pakistan whoever is
destroying pakistan has always been
destroying pakistan which is the
pakistani army and the isi when it comes
to the comedian actor zelinski who is
destroying ukraine mr zelensky is not in
power
he is just president of whatever
president right in name
he is president in name he is not in
control of what's happening
there was a coup in ukraine the maidan
coup which was engineered by the united
states
right and the democratically elected
president of ukraine was ousted in this
illegal unconstitutional coup
and
and who was it i don't even remember who
was the person who was put in place and
after that person it was
zelensky who has been appointed or put
in place as the president there's no
democracy there it looks like democracy
when you have all these elections but
the entire basis
is undemocratic and unconstitutional aku
so uh mr zelensky is not in power in
ukraine he has no real decision-making
ability he is simply a puppet of a
foreign power that's all he is so
understand this
mr imran khan was never in power in
pakistan and mr zelensky is not truly in
power he appears to be in power there's
a he's doing all these photo shoots for
vogue and all that he's just an actor
he's an actor who is acting as the
president
right that's what it is so you have to
look through these things
this is how they fool you
many of these people who are in power
are not really in power they are only
appointed they are they're presidents
and prime ministers in name
especially in nations that are
controlled by outside forces there are
so many of these yeah
and the real power is somewhere else the
real power lies somewhere else and these
presidents and prime ministers have no
ability to say no
to the ones who really control them so
that's how it is
okay this is by subhita devi mr david
reich research says indians have yamnaya
admixture this is the main narrative but
scandinavian genesis geneticist
published a paper
that says india do not have your
admixture dr david drake also claims r1
z93
subclade of r1a4 thousand years common
ancestor is french
geneticist published a paper which says
it is 15 000 years and so on and so
forth so on and so forth long long long
thing
what the the main question what is the
main question
okay whatever is the main question it's
a very long
wall of text i'm not going to go into
that the question is how old is r1a how
old is this z93 subclade and so on so we
indians love complexity we love to get
into the details
so what is this entire matter it's about
the aryan invasion migration
question
what is the origin of the indian people
are most indians descendants of foreign
invaders so-called aryans
that was the original thesis the
original theory which was propounded in
the 19th century by max miller and
various other
foreign
uh alleged historians and so on based on
various
claims and considerations and biblical
chronology and all that
so initially it was claimed by
foreigners that indians especially north
indians and western indians and other
indians as well are descendants of white
skinned foreign invaders who came in
from eastern europe
aryans they brought in the sanskrit
language they brought in hinduism so
hinduism and sanskrit are
invasive
forces they are the they are the they
are the language and the culture of
oppressors and colonizers
right so that was the claim then later
it became very clear there is absolutely
zero archaeological evidence of any
invasion whatsoever so then the story
was changed and they said it was not an
invasion it was a migration
they slowly came in and migrated and
that's how they and and yet the eventual
end result was the same they imposed
their foreign language sanskrit and
their foreign culture and religion
hinduism and the evil caste system on
the hapless native dravidians who are
the original natives of india right so
that is the migration claim now even
even there there is no evidence for a
migration because when there's a
migration there is a change in the
archaeological archaeological record
so now they are trying to base their
claims on they are now saying there are
multiple small waves of migrations and
there is a genetic imprint that trickles
into india and so on and so forth so
they are continuously changing the story
changing the story
and now that indians have caught on to
the genetic thing now they are making it
complicated so not just so the one of
the primary uh genetic lineages
patrilineal lineages in india
is the
r1a1a lineage
it is called r1a1a its parent is the r1a
lineage the parent of r1a is the r1
lineage the parent of r1 is the r
lineage and so on and so forth it all
dates back to the f lineage
which is ancestral to more than 90
percent of all males non-african males
who are alive today and the f lineage
originated in india
about 65 70 000 years ago and the oldest
non-african matrilineal lineages
also originated in india around this
time
m and n right so the question is so so
r1a has been mischaracterized as the
aryan gene and the thing about r1a is
that it's found in high concentrations
in the indian subcontinent and also all
the way in europe
so that's why it seems like you know it
could have come in from europe
there's a very significant concentration
of the r1a1a
imprint in eastern europe in in northern
europe in poland in germany in the
slavic regions etc then in india in
parts of iran
there's a whole continuum right so
that's why they say that you know there
was a migration
and now there's the the amnia story the
yamnia angle as well about 5000 years
ago there was a massive invasion
of brutal horse-riding warrior
conquerors
from the east into europe which totally
changed the genetic
uh demographics of europe
so the
older genetic demographics of europe
disappeared
the male lineages disappeared entirely
and they were replaced by these eastern
yamnaya male lineages which means these
invaders killed off all the men and
essentially took their women and and had
offspring with them that's what happened
right and this happened very rapidly
this was an unstoppable
invasion they have been called the most
brutal genocidal invaders of all time in
human history these yamnaya people the
question is who are these people and
then there is the question of the step
ancestry which comes into india so there
is obviously affinity between
the indian genetic lineages and various
genetic images which are identified as
belonging to the central asian central
eurasian step region
and so on
so what is the truth what is the where
does all of this originate right that's
the question and then the complicated
matters by saying there are there are
various subclades of r1a like r1az 93
and so on and so forth
so what's happening
so my my point is very simple instead of
going deeper and deeper into smaller and
smaller details you need to look at the
bigger picture the question is very
simple what is the origin of the r1a
lineage what is the origin where did it
originate we know
that it originated between 15 and 25 000
years before today right and it appears
that it originated in the indian sub
continent now we need more data
more data is forthcoming soon
i
[Music]
i am informed by very reliable and well
placed sources
that a new paper is going to be
published this year by indian scientists
i i know because i have spoken with
doctor niraj i'm in contact with him so
uh most likely this year
a new paper is going to be published
which is going to demonstrate
and prove that the r1a genetic lineage
originates in the indian subcontinent
how do you know a genetically niche
originates in a certain place
you know it
when that region geographical region has
the highest diversity
of that particular genetic lineage
wherever you have the highest diversity
is
always going to be the origin place of
that lineage and so let's have a little
patience
let's wait for a few months more let the
paper be published we all know that it
originates in india this is going to be
just the corroboration of what we
already know
other papers have already been published
that show that they demonstrate that the
r1a lineages are the oldest in india
but let's wait for this new paper to
come in with lots of more data which
will prove beyond any doubt that r1a
originates in india and some preparation
is already you know happening for this
uh let me share something with you all i
think i've shown this before but let's
let's bring this up once again
so
one of the major proponents
of the invasion hypothesis invasion myth
has been dr david reich
david reich
so david wright wrote a book in which he
has made these claims and he has also
hired a minion
an indian minion called tony joseph who
wrote a book of his own
about what what is that called the i
don't know what it's called it makes all
these weird claims all these fictitious
claims that indians originated outside
india you know in the step and all that
so this is a very recent lecture that dr
david reich gave
it was on the 12th of july
today is the 31st of july 2022 this
lecture was about
19 days ago yeah
what does dr david drake say in this
in this lecture so let me just read it
out it's just a couple of paragraphs so
bear with me
so the title is the genetic history of
the southern ark a bridge between west
asia and europe what does it say
we present an integrative genetic
history of the southern ark an area
divided geographically between west asia
and europe
but which we define as spanning the
culturally entangled regions of anatolia
and its neighbors in both europe and
west asia cyprus armenia iraq and iran
we employ a new analytical framework to
blah blah blah blah blah
and so on so forth a very detailed thing
our comprehensive sampling shows that
anatolia received hardly any genetic
input from europe
or the eurasian step
from the charcoal ethic to the iron age
this contract contrasts with
southeastern europe and armenia which
were impacted by major gene flow from
yamnaya step pastoralists
and there's another thing here
a striking signal of stepped migration
in the southern ark is evident in
armenia in northwest iran where
admixture with yamnia patrilineal
descendants
occurred
coinciding with the third millennium bc
displacement from the step still itself
and so on
uh what else does it say
okay so the
impermeability of anatolia to exogenous
migration contrasts with our finding
that the yamnaya had two distinct gene
flows
both from west asia suggesting that the
indo-anatolian language family
originated in the eastern wing of the
southern ark
and the steps served only as a secondary
staging area of indo-european language
dispersal this is all very complicated
but you know what he is trying to say mr
dr david reich
he is he is now saying he has changed
his entire tune
he is saying that the step
served only as a secondary staging area
for indo-european language dispersal the
indo-anatolian language family
originated in the eastern wing of the
southern ark what does it mean he's
saying it originated around iran
wait for a few months is gonna say it
originated further east from iran
iran is
a part of the indian subcontinent it is
it is
geographically connected to the indian
subcontinent it is an extension of the
indians of korean we all know what is
the origin of the iranian persian people
we know that
so now see the tune has changed he is
now saying he is now admitting
that the indo-anatolian language family
originated in the eastern wing of the
southern ark which is in iran
essentially is saying
and the step the step ancestry served
only as a secondary staging area of
indo-european language dispersal which
means that there was something before
the step ancestry now the only question
now
which needs to be answered
it is what is the ancestry of the step
ancestors
these so-called step step genes
where did they come from
he's clearly saying that the step is not
very originated
it's all going to circle back to india
wait for a few months
so that's what i will say about this we
can go into lots of small details about
r1a z93 and how old is that that is not
important
that is not important at all we need to
look at what is the origin of r and r 1
and r 1 a and r 1 b
the yamana where r 1 b
descendants of r1
what is the origin of r1a what is the
origin of r1
and what is the origin of r and i can
guarantee
wait for some time wait for a few months
wait for a few years by this day by the
time this decade is out it will be
proven
conclusively that r itself originates in
the indian subcontinent this is going to
be the end of the aryan invasion
migration tourism picnic theory once and
for all it's just a matter of time we
can already see the wheels in motion
even dr david reich is now admitting
this all originates in this
incredibly long winded complicated
convoluted fashion he's admitting
he's admitting that it all originated
he's now claiming iran
earlier they used to claim it was the
step the central age and the eurasian
step now they are saying it's iran a few
months or a few years down the line they
are going to admit that it came from the
indian subcontinent from india
it's going to happen and these
disposable minions like tony joseph will
be discarded
you know
tony joseph i i mean when his book came
out i read the entire book i wrote a
detailed review article which was really
scathing
but it was factual
okay i pointed out all the holes in the
claims that he has made
you can read it just google it right
google objective tony joseph review
so i wrote this article then we had
interaction on twitter i invited him for
a factual
polite
debate
you know on youtube
and let's discuss your book let's
discuss your book and let's go through
the evidence and see what makes sense
he refused he ran away
he wrote this book but he doesn't have
the confidence to defend it
so that tells you everything you need to
know about this entire matter
okay moving on
priyank says i read the post on twitter
by okay by whoever about a skull found
in the narmada belt which is dated to
about 1.5 to 2.5 lakh years
it is being said to challenge the out of
africa theory your thoughts okay let's
take a look at the nurbada man thing
um
so once again let me uh share me screen
with you all so this is the i believe
the original paper this is this dates
back to 1991
is the narmada hominid and hominid an
indian homo erectus
and
if you look at the abstract
it says that it suggests
it exhibits a broader suite of
morphological and menstrual
characteristics suggesting affinities
with early homo sapiens fossils
uh from asia europe and africa and so on
so forth so
so it seems to claim that it is
something like homo sapiens right so
that's what this paper from 1991 says
now let's look at a subsequent paper
it's not enough to look at just one
paper yeah we have to look at other
papers and what other people have said
so this is about this is from 1990
what's the year i think it's from 1998.
yeah it's 1998. antiquity of the dharma
the homo erectus early man of india so
over here it says it is homo erectus not
homo sapiens
it says that right
let's take a look at another
publication a much more recent
publication what does it say what does
it say now
this is from the smith smithsonian
museum this is up to date
uh it says it's about 300 000 years old
and it is homo erectus
so now today
today
in the 21st century in 2022 the
consensus is very clear it is homo
erectus not homo sapiens
all right
uh in 1991 the claim was made that it
was homo sapiens
later on the consensus was reached that
it is not quite homo sapiens it's
actually homo erectus homo erectus is is
an older more archaic version
of the homo various homo species right
it's an older species
it's not homo sapiens and we know that
homo erectus was present in in asia
in eurasia much before homo sapiens
uh entered eurasia about 70 or so
thousand years ago so the art of africa
migration is the out of africa is the
migration of homo sapiens the latest
migration before that we had homo
erectus in asia we know that we have we
have found it in
evidence of this in various parts of the
year
including in indonesia and other places
so it looks like the narmada human being
was homo erectus not homo sapiens that
seems to be the consensus among all the
scientists who have looked into this so
uh i don't know who has tweeted this i
mean uh and what claims have been made
i've not seen the tweet so i'm not gonna
comment about
that
but from whatever i am able to see here
i am obviously not an expert in this i
can understand what scientists write i
have not done the research myself so the
consensus
is that this is not homo sapiens it's
homo erectus now obviously things can
change
even scientists can be mistaken we know
what scientists have been claiming about
the about the iron invasion migration
thing they're wrong
and they know they're wrong now they're
changing the tune so it is possible that
in the future somebody may re-examine
this the remains and maybe a different
uh
conclusion could be drawn
but
from all the evidence that we have as of
today it is homo erectus not homo
sapiens and if it is homo erectus it
does not challenge the art of africa
theory all right that's all i can say
about this
naman johan was going through an article
about chohans having cultural
similarities with the hungarian paganism
and their culture
they drew similarities between the
chahamanas the chauhans of chakambari
and the white hounds their quran etc is
there any real possible connection
between the two or is the same
speculation so i don't know which
article you're referring to i have not
seen the article uh the homs did not
have any cold device
so who are the homes we are referring to
the homes are the hephthalites the the
shwetahones who invaded india in the
first half of the first millennium a.d
around the time that the gupta empire
was at its its peak the honors started
coming in from central asia they took
over parts of gandhara western india
then they started trying to invade india
india itself you know
mainland india itself they were repulsed
time and again by the gupta emperors
especially by skanda gupta the great
defender of india after the death of the
gupta the hornets the white hounds where
the shwetahones were able to
start conquering parts of india
and they entered india they ruled
various parts of india for some time
they
harmoniously adopted indian culture
except for one or two kings
mihirakula was a particularly nasty king
he was an atheist and he he oppressed
all indians buddhists hindus all yeah if
you want to draw a distinction between
buddhism hinduism but most huna kings
assimilated into indian culture they
became proper indians they all became
hindus essentially right
uh
we had the show so called uh turkish the
hindus the kabul tries who were hunts
who ruled in northwestern india
present-day afghanistan
and they defended india from the turkic
invasions
the later technical invasions and so
yeah that's what it was
so what was the culture of this people
it was what is now called tangerism so
the horns and the mongols have the same
ancestry the same origin the mongolians
practice today today if you look at
mongolian culture it's a beautiful
synchronous syncretic culture see a
syncretic mix of indian culture and
tangorism it has elements of the
angriest in the original culture of
mongolia
and elements of buddhism and hinduism
and you see a beautiful mixture of that
in mongolia today the
uh the horns
they also practice the same religion
fangirism now most people will tell you
that tangorism is a monotheistic
religion there is absolute nonsense
angrism is a polytheistic religion the
the two major deities are
the sky father thangari and the earth
mother umai
and there are a whole host of other
divinities there is ancestral worship
there is spirit worship there's nature
worship all of that is present in
thingism right
so uh it was a polytheistic culture it
is a polytheistic culture wherever it
still exists and the horns because our
polytheists they were able to assimilate
assimilated very easily into indian
culture hinduism buddhism whatever you
want to call it because it's all
polytheistic cultures are very similar
now uh so that's the similarity that you
can talk about uh
the hunts did not have kuladevi's
they did not have kuldevi's so that if
if a claim
of that sword has been made
i i have seen no evidence of that
antagonism there is no concept of cool
device and all that
and when it comes to the rajputs and
chahamanas other rajputs they are
descendants of
so who are the rajputs the chahamanas of
the chauhan's rajputs right it's a
rajput clan it's not a tribe it's a clan
it's a lineage so there are a number of
uh
such lineages which are now called
rajput lineages or clans who are the
rajputs the rajputs are the warrior
class but not the entire warrior class
the rajputs were the aristocracy the
ruling class among the warriors among
the so-called chatriers right that's
what they were so these are ancient
lineages that date back to vedic times
there could be a little bit of influx
from hunts or whatever
when the horns came and ruled over parts
of india for a small period of time they
did not come in enormous numbers and in
millions
their popul their numbers were dwarfed
by the indian population they were just
a small drop of water into the ocean
that is was indian population so if
there is any genetic genetic
contribution to the indian gene pool
from hons it is minimal negligible maybe
0.1 or so
and it's possible that some of them
after they assimilated into indian
culture and started ruling various parts
of india they would have claimed rajput
origin or traditional lineages because
as we know
parts
most of central asia was indian in
nature before the turkic invasions right
was the eastern part north east of the
himalayas
and uttara madra was the western part of
central asia and these were all
dynasties that that had indian origins
right
so the huns it's very conceivable that
they would have claimed indian origin
indian lineages and they would have said
that we are rajputs and maybe the indian
indian public may have accepted it and
maybe they slowly assimilated into
some of the rajput lineages
we know that some of the horns who ruled
over
certain parts of india
took up indian rajput surnames we know
that
and maybe they would have intermarried
among these various ruling aristocratic
plans it's centrally possible so that's
the extent to which there could be
uh intermingling or whatever but when it
comes to the chow hans they don't have
horny origin they may have a little bit
one percent maybe half a percent of
hunic
ancestry just a little bit because horns
may have intermarried
among them but that's nothing more than
that
so uh
so yeah there are some claims that
rajputs have skitian origins and hunik
origins
that
there could be just a little bit of
veracity to that
rajputs could have maybe half a percent
one percent of greek ancestry maybe one
percent skit an ancestry may be three
percent
kushan ancestry but overall these are
indian lineages that date back to very
very deep antiquity to the vedic edge
itself
okay so that's
what it is
attila the hun says the chinese never
wrote anything kind about the shionu or
the huns at any frame of time
the romans also never wrote anything
kind about the huns and even today in
brussels in the european union there is
hungarophobia
i wish you i wish you very much i wish
you and your people much good
and wealth thank you very much
so this seems to be somebody from
hungary well it's nice to hear from from
you sir
uh it is true that the chinese never
wrote anything good about the huns about
the shonu so the the ancestors of the
so-called homs are the show new which
who originated
in the northern regions of what is now
china what is present-day china which
was never
historically part of china
so if you go if you look okay i have not
shown the map today which is shocking
what am i doing i'm losing my touch i
need to show the map
where's the map
yes we need to look at the map when we
discuss these issues so this is the map
this is the world now let's go north of
india if you go north of let's say
manipur just keep going north keep going
north you will reach mongolia right
and this region
mongolia and north of mongolia the
siberian region this is the original
homeland of the uh mongolian and hundred
people and the turkic peoples and their
ancestors were called by the chinese as
the shionu
okay
so the chinese did not
obviously the chinese did not like them
the chinese wanted to suppress them
and they did that successfully for
centuries eventually there was a
backlash in the form of the great
genghis khan right
so uh the chinese regarded the chanu the
huns as barbarians
yeah and that's why they built the
so-called great wall of china and that
is the actual extent of the chinese
nation
right that that is the real border of
china the great wall of china
so the purpose of this great wall was to
keep the unwashed uncivilized barbarians
out they shown you out and you are right
sir the chinese never wrote any anything
good about the huns about the shonu the
romans also never wrote anything good
about those at the same time that the
white horns the shweta hunas were trying
to invade india at the very same time
they were trying
to uh
were to to invade
the roman empire
so so that was that is what was going on
right
uh the hons were trying to invade rome
and india at the very same time
so that's how widespread the where there
were nomadic people they were spread all
across eurasia and they were invading
rome and india at the same time the
romans never wrote obviously they never
wrote anything good about the horns
their homes were very successful in
their in their military campaign against
the romans
yeah
uh so the romans never wrote anything
good about those they also regarded the
homes as barbarians
india fought the huns but eventually
accepted them
and the homes assimilated into the
indian population
so you will never see anything bad
written about the huns from the indian
perspective apart from one king called
me which no one liked whom no one liked
he was uh well a nasty piece of work he
was an atheist and he oppressed
uh
various buddhist monks and monasteries
he oppressed the hindus and brahmanas as
well he oppressed everybody he was a
cruel guy
but most other honey rulers were
well they were good
they did not uh
you know they did not do anything that
would necessitate indians to write
anything bad about them one of the
kings who ruled in gandhar
his name was narendra de khingila
he is most likely the king who
commissioned the construction of the
great statues of the buddha in the
bamiyan region of gandhar present-day
afghanistan so as you can see they
adopted
indian culture wholeheartedly they
became
indians
they married among indians they and
and so that's how it was so
india treated the horns well and
india accepted the horns with open open
arms and today
you don't see any horns in india because
they're all assimilated
right and when it comes to the european
union yes there is a significant
hungerophobic
uh
sentiment in the eu
hungary
is a nation
whose uh
well that descends from the hunnic
invaders of europe that dates back about
a thousand or so years ago the name
attila is quite common in hungary was
one of the great hanukk
conquerors yes
so uh
yes the nation of hungary is descended
from
the
conquerors
of europe of various parts of europe
they eventually
adopted european customs they became
christians and all that but there is
this this sense in europe that
hungarians are are still
kind of outsiders
the way the europeans regard russia
there is a very similar attitude towards
hungary
if you look at western europe they
consider russia to be
a part of the east
they do not consider russia to be a
european
nation or culture it's an eastern
culture it's it's
non-european from the perspective of the
western european peoples and the same
attitude exists towards hungary as well
so there is an attitude of racism of
othering
the russians and the hungarians so yeah
there is there is indeed a fact that is
indeed a fact and it's it's i'm glad
that somebody is pointing this out
so so my dear friend i also wish you and
your people success and prosperity and
good health and wealth as well
siddharth says i have been wondering
that if the british empire did not have
india under the british raj during world
war ii would the allied forces have lost
to the axis
since india was a huge source of
resources and supplies for the war
if this hypothetical scenario did happen
how would it play out
when it comes to this two world wars
the world war one and world war two
world war one starts in 1914
and world war two ends in 1945. so this
was about a 30-year period of war
with a brief period of apparent peace
inter
inter bel interbellum so
from my perspective this world war one
and world war two were a continuation of
the same conflict the great european
tribal war that's what it was it was a
european tribal conflict and its roots
go go back to the 19th century even even
before that actually
so that's what it was
now
in world war one
the british had the indian the british
indian army at the disposal
nearly two million indian soldiers i
think it's 1.7 or 1.8 officially
million indian soldiers participated in
the war
and fought for the british and died for
the british in this war that's 17 or 18
lakh indian soldiers who fought for a
foreign power
on various parts of europe and africa as
well
yeah in world war one the british would
not have survived world war one if it
was not for the brave indian soldiers
and the indian soldiers were the best of
the lot the germans were frightened of
the indian soldiers
fought so many incredible battles the
battle of haifa in israel and various
other battles it was because of the
indian soldier that the british were
able to prevail at the end in world war
one the same goes for and when it comes
to world war one who was it that
recruited indian soldiers to fight for
the british
one of the major recruiters was sergeant
major mohandas gandhi
who actively recruited indians to fight
for the british
violence bang bang bang mr gandhi
yeah
interesting in world war ii which is the
second half of this conflict of the
european tribal war
i think about two and a half million
indian soldiers were made to fight for
the british that's 25 lakh
without the contribution of the indian
soldiers the allies would not have won
world war ii or world war world war 1 or
world war ii
and they also had the incredible
enormous amount of resources that they
could pillage from india
right
so had india not been part of the
british empire if they had the british
not been in control and occupation of
india they would not have been able to
prevail
in world war one or world war two there
is a fact and many british
uh
high-ranking generals etc have spoken
about this have written about this
that very not for the indian soldiers
the british would not have survived
these wars so that's a fact
undeniable fact
okay koustub says i have talked to a few
people living in balochistan pakistan
they said that in 1947 the khan of kalat
offered nehru to exceed
to accept balochistan to india but mr
nehru rejected this offer is it true
if yes it's another blunder by the great
chachaji
it is indeed true
let's take a look at what evidence we
have regarding this do we have
you know
this has been written about lots of
times but uh somehow people are not
aware of this
here's what happened i'm just showing
you one article you will find lots of
other articles if you will bother to do
your own research
so this is from the sunday guardian
nehru's balochistan blooper was as
disastrous as himalayan blunder and this
is a book that's been written about this
so if you read this article i'm not
going to read it out for you it's a very
lengthy article this is just one piece
of evidence you will see lots of other
articles which did which discussed this
issue with threadbare
what happened is that
uh um just take a look at this so the
khan of kalat in 1946 was a discussion
with the top congress leadership on the
fate of balochistan
one of his representatives met abdul abu
kalam azad
the then congress president but the
maulana questioned the very idea of
balochistan as an independent nation
uh
if a report by a british briton based
think tank the foreign policy center is
to be believed nehru returned the
accession paper signed by the khan of
kalat in 1947. see it's very clear
the khan of kalat the which this kala
thing this region was most of
balochistan
he
had two options he did not wish to
accept to pakistan
a he wanted to accede to india and if
that did not work he wanted to remain
independent he signed the document the
accession document that every other
princely state signed to become part of
india he signed it he sent it to india
to narrow and narrow send it back
nehru sent it back
balochistan wanted to be a part of india
mr nehru rejected that i don't know why
he would do such a thing
mr nero is is it i mean
i don't even know what to say about the
great magnificent magnanimous
incredible
mr nehru agree a truly great man
so yes it is indeed true that the khan
of kalat signed the accession papers the
document of accession to india
it was sent to mr nero and mr nehru sent
it back
right
so yes this is indeed a fact and this is
just one article there are books written
about this there are lots of other
articles written about this there is a
lot of documentary evidence for this
and yeah so it is indeed a fact that
balochistan could and should have been a
part of india but
mr nehru did not allow that to happen
the same way he did not allow gwadar to
become a part of india it was offered to
india for free by the sultan of oman he
refused
nepal wanted to rejoin india the king of
nepal requested mr nehru to allow nepal
to become again a part of india mr nehru
rejected that
he rejected
he gave away the great the magnificent
kabul valley a part of manipur for
centuries he gave it away to burma
he gave it to burma for free
yeah
and he gave away the cocoa islands to
burma
and so many other things i mean you
could have a
series of of episodes just about mr nero
and he's in his incredible
deeds
for india
rusal says what are your thoughts on the
nuclear bombing of japan in 1945 at the
end of world war ii was it justified
the
nuclear bombing of hiroshima and then
nagasaki
these represented
horrific war crimes
these are war crimes
they nuked civilians
they nuked unarmed men women and
children you have not seen the
photograph of the aftermath
those photographs are now
very hard to find on google
you know
those are horrific images you don't want
to see them
people whose skin has melted away and
was still alive
hundreds thousands of people like that
you know suffering and
who are going to die eventually but
they're suffering
the incredible agony
their skin has melted over their clothes
have melted into the skin in their flesh
this is what the americans did in
hiroshima and that's what they did in
nagasaki the ones who died immediately
were lucky
and even today you have all these
genetic defects because of the
uh the the
effects of the radiation
that lingered on in this region in these
two cities in these regions
these were unpardonable war crimes you
cannot do such a thing to civilians
similarly the fire bombing of the german
city of dresden
by the americans
was an
unpardonable war crime
once again you can look look up on
google image search
what happened in the city
you know
i don't know how many thousands of tons
of explosives
incendiary bombs were dropped on the
city
full of innocent
civilians
and and see what what happened there
these are war crimes you know that's how
it is in war the ones who win they
decide
who's who's the who's the criminals and
who are not
the greatest crime is to lose a war
you know
if you win you can make anything happen
so that's how it was so my views are
very clear these are war crimes that
have never been punished
that's it
and just to circle back about this it
doesn't mean that the japanese what they
did was not was was right
they also the japanese also the germans
also did unpardonable war crimes no
doubt about that
we know what the nazis did to the jews
and to the gypsies to the romani people
genocide
so that is obviously unpardonable what
the british did in india was was
genocide of a
much higher order right
that has never been punished that's not
even recognized today
what the japanese did in in eastern
asia's houses are in china in nanjing is
unpardonable
so everybody
committed war crimes but unfortunately
for some reason the focus is only on the
nazi war crimes and the japanese war
tribes what about the war crimes co
you know perpetrated by the allies but
the canadians which no one knows about
why the british
but the americans
no one talks about that that also is
part of history
and what they did is nothing but war
crimes
nuking a civilian population in an
entire city is a war crime of the
highest magnitude one of the worst
things you can do
and that's just what they did and they
got away with it scot-free
gore of gosavi says why do we admire
netaji subhash and rabos so much the ina
in spite of being brave courageous were
thoroughly decimated and so on and so
forth even after his death which is in
quotation marks the ii members were
jailed suffered terrible consequences
a leader leads his people to defeat in
two battles allows his people to be used
cannon fodder does nothing to ensure his
people's safety after death would he be
still called a great leader ps i love
and respect and admire netaji from the
bottom of my heart i'm just playing the
devil said okay sorry if it hurts
anybody's feeling okay
a good question we should certainly
examine this this question why do we
admire
vitaj sebastian rabos
despite the fact that he did not succeed
what was his objective
let's understand this what was the
objective
his objective was to liberate india from
british occupation through military
means
that was his objective
he tried to to play to go through the
traditional political route he was a
member of the congress he was ejected
from the congress by mohandas gandhi who
who engineered a political coup against
against
and then
realized that the political uh
route will not work and that's why he
went and explored other options the
military option he raised an army etc
so his objective was to liberate india
from
genocidal british occupation through
military means
and we know that he did not succeed he
failed right we know that he failed so
why do we still admire him
the reason
we admire
him
is because he had skin in the game
he was there on the front lines facing
the bullets he put his life on the line
repeatedly for the sake of his nation he
put his life on the line he did not care
whether he lived or died
he was willing to die for the nation he
led his soldiers from the front and he
was even willing to put his reputation
to the stake he was willing to stake his
reputation he did not care whether his
reputation would be tarnished
as long as he was able to serve his
nation and
he has been called all kinds of things
by indian politicians
the the indian communists called netaji
this is not my words it's the in the
words of the indian communist party
various parties they called him a
running dog of the japanese that's what
they called him
various other parties and other
politicians and other quarters have
called him um
they've called him a war criminal
because he was on the side of the axis
powers germany and japan he has been
called all kinds of things
people have tried to destroy his
reputation
he was fine with that he did not care
what happened to his reputation what
happened to his life as long as he was
able
to serve the nation
there are certain politicians
who sit somewhere far away and have have
people die for them right
so they will the so-called armed chair
generals who will draw lines on maps and
those lines on the map maps will cause
hundreds of thousands of soldiers to die
but they will not be there in the thick
of the battle right
there are most of these so-called
leaders are like that netaji was not
like that he was there he was there
facing the bullets facing the bullets
right he was there
so there is so much today's leaders can
learn from somebody like him
if you look at today's
politicians i would say 99
of them are
well they leave a lot to be desired
less maybe one percent of politicians
have some of the qualities
that neeta just
had
yes he failed and leaders must succeed
so yes he failed but you know what
we admire people who failed gloriously
because they tried their best
you cannot say the same about the
so-called other leaders of india the
other so-called leaders of india from
the 19th from from from the 1930s 1940s
etc how many
hours
days weeks did muhammad ali jinnah spend
in a british jail can someone answer
this question how many days
did mr jinnah spend in a british jail
mr gandhi
spent a significant amount of time in in
five star jails yes palaces but at least
you can say he was in jail
you know he he would have a morning walk
he would have his goat milk and he would
then
relax and write something and write
letters and all that mr gandhi spent
that sort of quality jail time it was
like a vacation for him mr nero also
spent time in jail but it was again
quality vacation time
mr jinnah did not spend a single day in
jail
mr bose faced bullets
he was in a submarine
he had to escape from house arrest
disguised as somebody else he had to
escape through northern india through
gandalf
through central asia all the way to
russia i believe then to germany from
germany he had to go all the way to
japan all in the service of the nation
he did everything he could he dedicated
his own life
to the nation he was willing to die for
the nation he was willing to have his
reputation ruined for the nation these
are the reasons we admire him for
show me another indian leader successful
or not who
had even 10 of nitaj's qualities
you won't find anyone like that so that
is the reason why we admire him yes yes
it's true he failed
he failed because he did not have the
resources that that the empire had at
its disposal
right
but he tried and most likely he knew
that he may fail
but he still tried
so that's why we admire him
so that is why he is one of the one of
the few leaders
of the 20th century and later
from india that we actually can truly
admire okay
okay this question again pawan says
telugu is older than tamil why do you
people always ignore telugu gotham says
sanskrit has ancient dravidian
linguistic substratum in it
and tamil has a lot of sanskrit
loanwords
in it so no need of fighting both are
pretty connected languages both are
native to india see this is
an ongoing topic of
people keep fighting about this i see
this in the comments every day on my
channel in other places
and and there is this constant fight
about which is the oldest language which
came first which came later
and there is this very strong
uh dravidianist feeling that tamil is
the oldest language of the history of
humanity and so on
so
i have been saying this from episode one
of the ask a widget show stop fighting
about this it doesn't matter we are all
the same people with the same genetics
the same ancestry the same culture same
everything and yet the fight goes on and
on and on and on so
so let's address this first of all the
the this entire thing about the
dravidian
linguistic family or whatever that is a
myth
so see the official version is that
sanskrit is part of the indo-european
language family apparently
and tamil telugu kannada tulu
etc are part of the so-called dravidian
language family
and these two are different language
families the truth is
that
sanskrit
and tamil
have much more in common than sanskrit
in german or sanskrit and latin or
sanskrit than any other indo-europe
so-called indo-european language
there is much more in common between
sanskrit and tamil than between any
sanskrit and any other indo-european
language there is much more in common
between marathi and tamil or gujarati
and kannada or or or hindi and and
telugu
then between the indian languages and
the indo so-called indo-european
languages
so these
all these presuppositions have to have
to be re-examined a priori we need to
start to to re-examine the linguistics
of india a priori
with fresh with a fresh perspective from
with a fresh
set of eyes from a scientific
perspective from a panini perspective
not from the occidental western
perspective not from the european
perspective so that's number one i do
not agree with this indo-european
language family nonsense and the
dravidian language family nonsense
there is an indian language family and
all languages are interrelated now the
question of telugu is it older than
family let's take a look at what
evidence we have
is telugu older than tamil so let me
share some of my
some of
some of these articles yes
so this is an article from the hindu it
is behind a paywall i am not going to
subscribe to them but it says that
telugu is four 2400 years old says the
asi
okay that is what the asi says it's one
uh article from the hindu from the from
2007.
once again this is the different article
which also says that the asi has
determined that the
what seems to be the oldest inscription
in telugu in archaic ancient telugu in
uh in a certain variant of the brahmi
script is 2400 years old
okay let's take one more article into
consideration
brahmi footprint triggers centuries old
telugu enigma so once again it dates
back to about 400 bce this is an article
from the times of india
yes so that's what we have and so on so
forth so it's clear that the oldest
evidence of telugu dates back to about
two thousand four hundred years before
today and it's in a place called
bhattipralu
but
it should be somewhere here yeah the
village of bhattipulu in guntur district
okay
400 or so bc
now what is the oldest tamil inscription
that we have i think it's not as as old
as this so this news
of the bhatti produ inscription came up
became known
in i think 2007 or so
right and later on there have been
claims that have been made that tamil is
older than that but i have yet to see
the evidence so the oldest evidence of
tamil dates back to about 200 bc or 300
bc
and the
telugu inscription dates back to 400 bc
so from the hard archaeological evidence
it's clear that telugu seems to be older
than
tamil now if you look at tamil tradition
we have the uh
the the sangam tradition the sangam
literature there were three sangam eras
sangha mira one second mira two
sangamira three the latest one dates
which dates back to about 300 bc
is the third sangamira which is the
historical sangamira and apparently
there were two sangha miras before that
and if you add up all the dates it dates
back to if if if you are to believe what
is said it dates back to almost nine
thousand or ten thousand bc
so that is the oral
claim that is made that tamil is that
old nine thousand ten thousand bc you
know what
one should not disregard these these uh
these oral traditions it is possible
that tamil may be ten thousand years old
it is also possible that telugu itself
may be ten thousand years old now
so but the but the hard evidence
that we have the oldest
inscriptional evidence that we have
anywhere in the world of telugu in tamil
shows that telugu is older
okay but
400 bc older and older than the oldest
tamil inscription
now when it comes to the actual
sanskrit words of other languages the
that that controversy i have always said
that let's not
make a big fight of this we are all the
same
but if you really want to get into this
okay if you really want to get into this
matter of what is older tamil or
sanskrit or telugu
it's been established now that the
oldest inscriptional evidence says that
telugu is older than sunscreen now if
you want to do a sanskrit vampire thing
yeah you want to do that
the oldest
tamil period is called what
what does this word sangam mean
community
is sangam
a tamil word
unfortunately it's a sanskrit word
so the oldest tamil period has a
sanskrit name sangam
what is the oldest tamil literature
that told a kapiam
yes the oldest literary text available
in the entirety of tamil history the
toll kapiam
the word told
means old or ancient
what is the word kapiam mean
kapiam
is that a tamil word
it's a sanskrit word
so the oldest tamil era has a sanskrit
name sangam the oldest tamil literature
is the told kavyam which again has a
sanskrit name
so
you know if you look at these things
different fact
other facts come to light i don't want
to get into all this i am i'm not in
favor of these unnecessary and pointless
fights i am sure the tamil and sanskrit
emerged maybe in parallel maybe both are
ancient languages
so as far as we know sanskrit is the
oldest language in humanity in human
history oldest known language maybe
tamil is also that old possibly maybe
telugu is older
the evidence that we have shows that
telugu seems to be older inscriptionally
than tamil and if you look at the
evidence from tamil names from the
sangam literature name and told kavyam
it's clear that
sanskrit may have come before tamil but
we don't have a hard evidence of these
things so my point is very simple let's
stop fighting amongst each other we are
the same people
we are one civilization
if you look at indian history of the
past let's say only three thousand years
you will see migrations within india
all across india north to south south to
north east to west
if you look at sangam literature they
talk about lands north of the himalayas
yeah tamil literature
you talk you if you look at sangha
literature he talks about the vedas or
the rishi munis
let's stop getting into all these
unnecessary political fights politicians
make people fight in order to gain
something for themselves and that's what
we are seeing in the south in the
southern part of india the dravidian
movement
they are trying to deny their own
history that's what's happening
so we need to stop fighting amongst each
other we need to work together and take
our civilization forward
right that's all about this matter
okay aman says
why were the first indian military heads
army
navy air force even after india's
independence by whether the british why
the english
what sort of independence is this
is it true
after 1947
the heads of the army indian army indian
navy indian air force were the british
uh who was the first governor general of
of independent india
it was that fellow right mountbatten
lord mountbatten why was an englishman
the governor general of india after
india became apparently independent
the first governor general of pakistan
after 1947 was muhammad ali jinnah
so why wasn't an indian appointed as the
governor general of india
instead of an englishman so yes the
first governor general of india of
independent india supposedly indeed in
india was an englishman is that
independence not quite it doesn't look
like independence to be doesn't sound
like independence let's take a look at
the army navy air force yeah let's see
if you can find a list of indian
heads of army and all that let's see
let's take a look
we can certainly find that very very
readily online
let me share the screen
list of indian chiefs of army staff
1947-2021
so let's see who we have 1947 15th
august onwards
general sir robert lockhart
that's not an indian name
48-49 general sir roy
buker
so yes it's clear that you had even
after 1947 you had two englishmen
who were at the head with the head of
the indian army
let's take a look at the air force shall
we
what do we have
list of air chief marshals of india 47
to 221
1947 15th august sir thomas walker
elmhurst
then ronald ivelo chapman 950 1951 sir
gerald ernest gibbs
yeah until 1954
good god
these are all englishmen
why was it so in an independent india
let's take a look at the navy shall we
list of chiefs of the naval staff of
india 47 onwards
15th august onwards rear admiral john
talbot saviniak hall
then 48 to 48 rear admiral the same guy
then vice admiral william edward parry
until 1951 then until 1955 sir charles
thomas mark pisee whoever the hell that
is
then 55 to 55
mark pizzi then robert
stephen
hope carl until 1958
so it is very clear
that even after india's so-called
independence
india had a foreign
governor general
and
foreign
chiefs of the army navy and air force is
that independence that is why people ask
the question what really happened in
on what terms did india gain its
so-called independence
what changed after india's so-called
independence you still had british
people
at the heads of the army navy and air
force you had a british
governor general you had the same
british institutions in india which
still exist today
the indian penal code dates back to 1860
who wrote that the british who wrote
that
the infamous lord
macaulay
right
and that still exists today the indian
constitution
is of foreign origin what really what
did india really become independent
that's the real question we have to ask
ourselves are we really independent even
today
what changed after independence did the
education system change
did we get to learn the true history of
india no we are still taught lies
nothing has changed india is still
deeply deeply and thoroughly colonized
and you can see that in me as well so
that's where we are so good question we
need to introspect about these things
okay dominic says what if sri lanka
today had a different different
neighboring country like the u.s china
or russia in place of india
would sri lanka
still be independent today would these
countries have taken a different
approach towards sri lanka's crisis if
they were in the place of india this is
an excellent question
what if instead of india sri lanka was
the neighbor of the u.s or china or
russia
in the 1940s
what would have happened then
you know
after india became independent
supposedly
india's ambassador to the ussr met
the the head of state
mr joseph stalin the dictator of the
ussr yes
and they were looking at the map of
india and all that and
joseph stalin pointed out a small island
to the south of india and he asked the
indian ambassador what is this what is
the name of this small indian island
and the indian ambassador said this is
not an indian island this is an
independent nation sri lanka
and stalin said
why is it independent
and that's the that's a good question
why was this small island
right
next to india
independent for what reason
why was it not part of india mr salan
could not understand it for the life of
himself
right
why was sri lanka
kept separate from india it was it has
always been part of india's in the
indian civilization it was part of
various indian empires the chola empire
and so on yeah it's the same people the
same languages why is it an independent
nation so if it was china instead of
india china would have immediately
reabsorbed sri lanka and made trilinka
part of china if it was the ussr instead
of india the ussr would have obviously
absorbed sri lanka within itself and the
same would apply to the u.s the us is an
expansion of germanic power
we know what they've done to mexico
texas was part of mexico california was
part of mexico new mexico was part of
mexico the americans fought wars with
the mexicans and took away all these
territories and so on and so forth
yeah so
had it been another country instead of
india that was next to sri lanka sri
lanka would not be independent today
yeah
and uh yeah so that's that's the answer
the current crisis is a whole different
story but historically
sri lanka has been extremely lucky that
it is an independent nation and maybe
not so lucky i mean see what happened
so yeah
ronit says you said that aircraft
carriers are obsolete in this age of
modern warfare however isn't aircraft
carrier important part of blue water
navy extending the range of attack for a
country using it against another country
as for their threat of submarines can't
a pair of anti-submarine corvettes be
employed along the carriers and aircraft
carriers can be protected by missiles by
using anti-air missiles through vls
systems present in aircraft credits
itself you know what
all nice and good hypothetically
when was the last time
an aircraft carrier was attacked was was
caught in open combat when was the last
time this happened
during the vietnam war
or or in the in the in the run-up to the
vietnam war
it was an american aircraft carrier that
had to face enemy fire what happened it
was decimated and destroyed
after that
no aircraft carrier has actually come
under enemy fire
yeah
aircraft carriers are nice when you have
overwhelming superiority and no real
uh threats
for instance
let's look at a different platform the
so-called um not the so-called the
drones
the americans of the predator drone and
the reaper drone and all that that that
loiter about 10 kilometers up in the sky
nobody can see nobody can hear it and
and they rain down missiles on
terrorists and all that
they do it with impurity because they
have they don't face any threat
if somebody had the wherewithal to fire
an anti-aircraft missile that thing it
would not stand a chance
so there are certain weapon systems that
work brilliantly when there is no threat
to them
these drones the predator drone the the
reaper drone they don't stand a chance
if an anti-aircraft missile has fired
them so the americans use them
on nations where there is no such system
of air defense
they use that in afghanistan in pakistan
the pakistanis allowed that had the
pakistanis fired anti-aircraft missiles
of these drones those drones would have
been blown out of the sky
similarly
when it comes to aircraft carriers
the last time an aircraft carrier came
under fire was many many decades ago
it is just a mathematical calculation
of how to destroy an aircraft carrier
yes you can defend aircraft carriers
with anti-missile missiles
yeah you can have a whole ring of
destroyers around an aircraft carrier
which carry these missiles and try to
safeguard it
it's just a question of numbers let's
say you have five destroyers each
contains each carries 50 missiles that
two that's 250 missiles
so each of these missiles can let's say
take down an incoming missile which
means that if you fire 250 missiles at
the aircraft carrier those missiles will
be intercepted and destroyed assuming
100 interception rate
so all you have to do to destroy the
aircraft carrier is fire 251 missiles
it's just a mathematical calculation
that's all
eventually your missile defenses will
run out
that's how it is
and not every nation can afford to have
so many missiles in defense of an
aircraft carrier and to and to place so
many destroyers
in around in order to defend an aircraft
carrier
and it's even easier to destroy an
aircraft carrier with a nuke
all you have to do is detonate a new 10
kilometers away
or five kilometers away far away from
the range of the incoming missiles and
the nuclear explosion will disable all
the ships
it's so easy to take out an aircraft
carrier you have no idea
aircraft carriers are massive
slow moving
lucrative targets
i mean just imagine the
the effect on a nation's morale
if a 10 billion dollar aircraft carrier
is destroyed
it's such an incredibly large investment
right
and and the americans have aircraft
credits that cost 10 billion plus
dollars in the case of india our
aircraft carriers cost four five billion
dollars that's a huge amount of money
you cannot acquire a hundred missile
boats for the same cost each missile
boat can have three missiles on it
brahmos missiles it's 300 missiles and
you can deploy it over a wide
extent of the indian ocean that's how
you make the indian ocean your strategic
backyard or you could acquire submarines
for that cost
you can acquire a high-class submarine
high quality submarine for a hundred
million dollars
there are certain submarines that you
can acquire for just 100 million dollars
so you could acquire 40 or 50 submarines
for the cost of one aircraft carrier
just imagine how much lethality you're
gaining for that
so
i know people will not agree with me
people will say that i am
an armchair general or whatever you
don't agree with me
well other people have said the same
thing on this channel dr edward luther
one of the greatest geo strategists of
all time he came on this channel and he
said the same thing
that the aircraft carrier is obsolete
that guy knows what he is talking about
he has seen
action
in wars he has designed weapons
he has advised prime ministers and
presidents
in a variety of nations he still does
that actively he knows what he's talking
about he came on this channel he spoke
with me for more than an hour he said
the same thing aircraft carriers are
obsolete
the aircraft carrier was the principal
ship
of the 20th century in the 21st century
the principalship of any navy is the
submarine
submarines are far more dangerous they
are invisible very hard to detect
and they can be lethal
and they can take out aircraft carriers
you you you can place
a nuclear warhead on a torpedo and
detonate it one kilometer below an
aircraft carrier and just imagine what
it will do with the aircraft carrier
so that's why i say this that aircraft
carriers are obsolete you can put as
many arguments as you want i can destroy
all the arguments
we need to stop investing in these
incredibly expensive white elephants
you know learn the lessons from the
russia ukraine conflict
quantity has a quality of its own don't
concentrate your lethality distribute
your lethality widely that's what we
need to do but unfortunately our
planners
whoever it is is still stuck in the 20th
century mindset
i don't know what it will take to change
this maybe a war
you know wars are not always bad things
i'm i'm not in favor of wars but
sometimes
you need that to wake you up i don't
know i wish that there is no war ever
but we need to wake up and we need to we
need to
enter
and embrace the 21st century right now
we are still stuck in the 20th century
mindset unfortunately
okay man vashishta says
it is said that during world war 1
germany tried to send a message to the
mexicans in order to gain their support
to fight the us which was helping
britain at the time but the english
intercepted the message and showed it to
the president of the u.s woodrow wilson
who after that officially declared war
on germany considering this if the
message had not been intercepted do you
think mexico and germany could have
defeated the us
because at the time the us was not a
great
powerful military power it had only
these many active and reserve military
personnel combined okay so it is alleged
that the germans during world war one
sent a telegram or a message of some
kind to the mexicans which was
intercepted by the british
who passed into on to the americans the
germans were trying to instigate the
mexicans against the us
and they were proposing that the germans
and the mexicans should should attack
the us jointly or something to the
defect and this was apparently the
tipping point which induced the
americans to officially declare war on
germany which eventually or at the end
of the day
contributed to the destruction of the
german military campaign and the defeat
of germany
so that's what it said
um the thing is this the americans after
this happened officially declared war on
germany but they were already aiding
the uk
they were sending supplies
to the uk
uh weaponry ammunition
tons and tons hundreds maybe thousands
of tons of food supplies
that is the reason the british were able
to hold out against the german attacks
right
without this u.s aid which went on
for years
the the uk the the british would have
would have uh capitulated much earlier
they have never captured capitulated
thanks to the americans thanks to
american support so even though the
americans had not officially declared
war on germany they were aiding
germany's enemy
actively
repeatedly and the germans were aware of
this they had this wolf pack there these
wolf packs these these u-boats
right undersea boats submarines which
were patrolling the atlantic ocean which
were taking down
u.s shipping which was aiding the uk the
americans protested the germans toned it
down
but eventually the americans entered the
fray so we don't know what is the truth
behind this maybe the germans did
ask the mexicans to get involved in this
or proposed
some kind of alliance
so let's say this message had not been
intercepted
do i think mexico and germany could have
defeated the us unlikely
the u.s
has an entire continent at their
disposal they have a much even at that
time they had a much greater
industrial base than the mexicans they
had
almost unlimited resources mexico was
much smaller and much weaker than the us
so even if the germans had joined hands
with the mexicans it is an it is
unlikely that they would have
made a significant dent on on american
on the us yeah
the germans did consider attacking the
us from the sea
the german
navy was one of the most powerful navies
in the world at the time the germans
were pioneers of of uh submarine
technology under sea board technology so
they had considered very seriously
various scenarios in which they could
attack the us east coast
from the atlantic ocean
but even if they had done that it would
not have made much
much of a difference to the americans
because they have such strategic depth
the entire continent from coast to coast
east coast to west coast
and
i don't think the mexicans were any
match for the american military even at
that point
so uh
so i think this was merely a pretext for
the americans to officially enter the
war
even after they declared war it took
them a few months to start to actually
get involved but yeah it eventually led
to the
defeat of the germans so i don't think
even if this message was not intercepted
even if the mexicans agreed and attacked
the us i don't think it would have made
much of a difference it would have
eventually led to mexico losing more
territory
that's all it would have
uh culminated in
okay two questions randhir says please
tell this please speak about the origin
of the meter people of manipur it is
said they weren't hindus earlier it was
king
uh gareb navas who introduced hinduism
then what was the religion
and lan chimba says what's your take on
the theory of tanja leela pahma
who ruled ancient manipur from 1445 bc
to whatever
is a descendant of the tang shang
dynasty he said by some stories that he
is from tang tribe
uh why did if he is a descendant of this
this dynasty why did his son write the
rules of sagal ganja in meeting
okay
the question is about the origin of the
metis people of manipur and the
people are the manipuris
right in the manipur region you have
different tribes and you you have the
mete people who are not a tribe who are
a larger community they have a history
that
seems to date back at least three and a
half thousand years
so they have a royal chronicle called
kumbaba which is a chronicle or whole
lineage of all the kings of the of of
the manipur region of manipur
the mete kings in one version it dates
back to about two thousand years before
today in another version it dates back
to three and a half thousand is before
today so 1450 approximately bce right
and the uh
the
originator of the
manipuri people is
is the legendary pakhangba who is the
snake king or the dragon king he's
depicted as a dragon
in manipur manipuri heraldry and all
that
so uh
he is believed to have ruled manipur to
about foreign
in about 1450 or so
bc
yeah
so what is the truth behind this is he a
descendant of the tang shang dynasty or
whatever there's no there is absolutely
no evidence for that
there are various historians who make
all kinds of ridiculous claims and it
gets published and then it becomes like
fact you know part of the existing
literature but what is the evidence
that uh pakhanba was a part of so-and-so
dynasty or or ex-dynasty or white nst
what is the evidence for that
there is zero evidence for that zero
there is no archaeological evidence for
that there is no literary evidence for
that yeah there is nothing in the
literature of the manipura people that
says that kangba or his ancestors came
from somewhere else nothing
so uh there is zero evidence for this
thing
uh what is sakura kanji it is polo
circle kangjai is the game of polo which
originated in manipur who knows how many
thousands of years ago
so maybe two thousand years ago or maybe
three and a half thousand years ago so
the origin of polo is in manipur it's
not in
armenia or azerbaijan or turkey or
persia whatever it's in manipur it's the
oldest game in this region
one of the oldest games sports the
british came to india they occupied
manipur
killed the king
hanged him in the general and then they
found the sport and they adopted the
sport and they started playing it and it
was the sport of the royalty and all
that polo
so uh
and the other question is about the
origin of the media people so we don't
quite know what is the origin they have
been in the region in the manipur valley
region the impalvary region in the
overall larger region around that
around three and a half thousand years
at least uh
one of the ways of knowing or deducing
the origin is to do genetic testing and
i don't think anybody has done any any
significant amount of serious testing
of the genetic lineages of the manipuri
people so we don't know
if that happens in the future we will
have a better idea of what the
migration routes were like we all know
that the history of the human species is
a history of migrations 70 000 years ago
the first humans came into this indian
subcontinent and from there they spread
out to various places so eventually it
all dates back to that
so the history of the meti people in
this region in
the far east of india goes back at least
three and a half thousand years ago so
that is that is very ancient it's older
than rome it's older than greece yeah so
i think
that's that's old enough for us right
what happened before that we can
try to reduce through genetic analysis
uh what is the religion
well the manipuri has had their own
religion
their own
their own culture polytheistic culture
it is now everything is in ism nowadays
you know so it's called sana mahism like
hinduism buddhism jainism psychism
tangorism sanama ism that sort of thing
so there
the original culture or religion of the
manipuri people is
the worship of sana mahi
and the entire pantheon of divinities
that uh
around that there is also ancestor
worship there is nature worship and so
much more so it's just like any other
polytheistic culture like tangerism
shinto etc in japan see there are
incredible parallels between
uh sanam and shinto so shinto is the
original
uh
culture or religion polytheistic belief
system in japan
later on buddhism came into japan so
sana the the shinto
belief system
was more closer to hinduism than
buddhism so they they the japanese
so buddhism as kind of you know
a lightweight version version of what
they already had but eventually buddhism
became a big thing in japan and today
what you have is a beautiful syncretic
mixture of shinto and buddhism that is
the mainstream culture in japan today
right similarly uh hind what we call
hinduism is a it it became a thing
during the time of uh pamela about 300
400 years before today i don't remember
the exact date about 300 or so years
before years before today
so this guy pamela
took on this very strange name of gareb
nawaz personate name yeah
and he adopted
gaudiya vaishnavism as the official
state uh religion around this time yeah
so even today in manipur sanam mahism
isn't dead
people who practice hinduism vaishnavism
they also practice animalism so it's
it's it's syncretized just like shinto
and buddhism syncretized
with elements of hinduism very much yeah
in japan the same way you have a
a mixture a syncretic admixture of of
sannamaism and gaudiya vaishnavism
in many more in manipur today so that's
what it is
so that i hope explains
the scenario in this manner
alpha says why are all tribals dark
skinned
so how do we define i i expect you
talking about the indian subcontinent
how do we define a tribe
a tribe is a group a small reasonably
small group of people that is isolated
from the rest of humanity
that is a tribe
so why are all tribals dark-skinned is
it is it true that all tribals are
dark-skinned
let's take a look at a certain
a certain tribe shall we
have you heard of the kalash tribe
the kalash tribe lives in northwest
india which is currently part of
pakistan temporarily for us for a brief
period of time
so the kalash people
are they they meet the definition of the
of the term tribe they have been
isolated in the in the mountains of this
region for a very long period of time
they hardly mixed with others with with
outsiders
this is what they look like
and some people claim that they are the
descendants of greek people well if you
look at the people of greece they don't
have blonde hair
and blue or green eyes
the people of greece have typically on
average have light brown skin and dark
hair and dark eyes so so these people
and if you these people have
the colors people their genetic testing
i mean their
genetic analysis has been done
and they are mostly of indian origin
yeah
so this is what indian tribals look like
the the the kalash tribe
there are other tribes as well
konyak
so in in north east india
in nagaland you have the cognac people
so this is what they look like they're
not quite dark skinned are they yeah
and we have other tribes as well what
about the bill people
so the bill people are classified as a
scheduled tribe
they live in central india western india
etc are they dark skinned
look at these ladies here i think
they're bill bill people look at these
people here look at this lady
some of them do have some some more
darker skin some of them have fair skin
so you know
it's it's wrong to generalize things
like this
yeah in india you have all kinds of
people with all kinds of different
appearances light skin dark skin even
the so-called tribal people come in all
varieties light-skinned people
dark-skinned people there are some
people who have darker skin and all and
so on but you can't generalize in this
manner all right so that's that's what i
would like to say
okay koldeep says
um
are the rig vedic nagas in the
present-day nagas the same people i read
somewhere that ma that maharashtra was
the home of the rig with ignagas
am i missing something is it all
unrelated is the name of coincidence and
so on
today's nagas are the people of the
region which is of the state that is
called nagaland yes and some regions
around that
these naga tribes people they also live
east of the border in myanmar etc yeah
so uh
those are the people of nagaland
now there is this mention of the naga
people from the rig in the
as well
in the mahabharata
in the ramen era etc these are different
peoples
the term naga for the people of present
day nagaland is a very recent
term it was created very recently i
think it is the british occupiers of
india
who gave these tribes
that this name of nagas
i don't know why they were called nagas
maybe
see the british were
racist people
they did not have a lot of respect for
the people of india
so it is possible that they called these
people nagas before they because
possibly because they wore less clothes
in because of the climate
so naga nagna means naked right in in
sanskrit so maybe naga means that maybe
that's why the british called them nagas
the british were racist and
disrespectful to indians and this is
possibly one of the examples of that
so uh
the the people of nagaland
were called nagas uh
in the 19th century before that we don't
know what they were called i think in
manipur the maite people called them the
various how tribes how so that is the
term that the mete people the manipuri's
had for the various tribes of this
region
the uh
the mao tribe the the
the maring tribe
and
various other tribes of present-day
ireland so all these people
all these various tribes lived in
different different parts of this region
many of them spoke different languages
they all had their own beautiful
indigenous culture that has been stamped
out totally
so these are not the rig with ignaga
people
right
the redmi naga people were a whole
different people we don't know who they
were i'm not sure if
maharashtra present day maharashtra was
the home of these people i'm not sure
about that
so i think
uh who they were is still a mystery
and obviously if they existed many
thousand years ago
then most indians today would have some
of some ancestry from them as well
so yeah that's what it is so present day
nagaland is not the same as the people
of the rigveda those nagal it's it's
totally different and totally unrelated
shruti says
thank you please let us know the list of
books and resources
needed to start learning world history
uh
how did i start learning world history
there is this series of books by will
and ariel durant
called the story of civilization
i think it's a 12 set book 12 volume
book set i think
if i'm not mistaken maybe 10 maybe 12
it's a big bunch of books the story of
civilization by will and ariel durant
it's an old
uh publication it's a i think the last
uh
the last version the last book among the
set was published i think in 1970s
so you could consider it to be somewhat
outdated but history is history so
that's
one of the first resources i had at my
disposal
so maybe you could start there it's it's
quite voluminous but it's it's it's
great for learning history and i think
it may be kind of out of print or if it
is available for purchase it may be very
expensive but i would say that if you
are reasonably resourceful you must be
you should be able to
acquire you should be able to get your
hands
on these books
so i could recommend the story of
civilization for world history yeah
and also the story of world history by
by h.g wells
which was written
a very long time ago and yet it's a good
book
so uh so that's a couple of
recommendations i would make but i
overall i would say read everything you
can
you read everything you can get your
hands on
and give yourself 10 years it's not
something you can do in a couple of
weeks there are no shortcuts to learning
world history it's a work in progress i
am still learning world history there's
still a lot for me to learn
so yeah so i can give you a couple of
recommendations and the overall larger
recommendation i would give is to read
as much as you can read everything you
can and slowly slowly you will develop
more and more knowledge
okay all the best
gs sci says you mentioned about rrr we
did not get to know whether you have
watched it we want you to see and enjoy
it as much as we enjoyed it i've watched
it i did not watch it in a theater i
missed it i typically don't watch movies
much these days whether it's hollywood
whether it's indian movies because
even hollywood has become garbage
nowadays the multiverse of misery and
whatnot
and bollywood is like beyond repair
and even other
parts of other other other woods
tollywood gollywood whatever it is i
don't really watch it but so that's why
i missed rr when it was out there in the
in the cinemas
but then i heard good things about it so
i watched it online and i think it's a
brilliant movie great movie
i think baahubali was i i've seen
baahubali part 2 in a on the big screen
it was i think more enjoyable than rrr
but rr is also
a very nice movie i think it's caught on
in the u.s for some reason the west has
discovered this movie and they are they
seem to be very very
enthusiastic about it
so yeah it's good to see that
and i think it's a very nice movie very
enjoyable movie the biggest sin
a movie can make
is to bore the audience is to bore the
viewer and rrr does not do that
it's a nice fast-paced movie it doesn't
bore you even once
it it keeps moving along it's got a very
clear storyline the protagonists know
what they want and the antagonist also
knows what he what they want so it's
very clear the conflict is very clear
very nice storytelling good action
little bit over the top but that's fine
that's fine so very entertaining doesn't
bore you at all good movie i liked it i
loved it
ice cube says your views on the film
rocketry
okay before i answer this let me say
that uh
it's good this movie was made uh
we now by now know that
dr nambi narayan was
was unfairly targeted he was victimized
and it was all a political conspiracy of
some kind
and it's good that this has been
recognized that he has been
rehabilitated he has been honored by the
indian government he was offered
he
i don't know which award he got but he
got the award at the hands of the
president of india so it's really good
that he has been honored
his reputation has been uh
has been restored
uh
the government in a way has apologized
to what happened to him for what
happened by giving him this honor and
all that so it's really good
that uh he got some justice i'm really
glad to see that and i'm glad they've
made a movie about him okay so that's
what i'll say in the beginning now i did
watch the movie
it was not a well-made movie not a great
movie
extremely long drawn out movie
it it kind they tried to depict him as
some kind of a james bond figure the guy
is an engineer a rocket scientist it's
not a james bond they have tried to
depict him at the heart of every single
advance that happened in indian
in in israel he was at the forefront of
everything he was kind of a james bond
figure who got technology from different
countries in a very stealthy manner come
on make it factual
and it's a very long drawn out very
boring movie unfortunately
right so i'm talking about the movie
the movie the movie isn't great i did
not like it i i know i'm going to get
some hate for this for what i'm saying
because people seem to have loved the
movie
it plays on your emotions indians are
very emotional people so maybe it makes
sense from that perspective i did not
enjoy the movie but i am glad the movie
has been made i mean how many rocket
launches have they shown in the movie
one in the beginning and that's it
so why did they name the movie rocketry
so um just a little bit of nitpicking
overall i'm glad they made a movie in
which they have shown at least the fact
that
dr nami narayan was victimized
unfairly unjustly complete lies
and i'm also very glad that he has been
honored by the government of india
so all that is good the movie itself is
nothing to write home about very i found
it boring and if somebody is offended by
it by that i mean no
i mean no disrespect to anybody
whatsoever i have the highest of regard
for dr nam binary and his contribution
to
the cause of the nation
that's it
hershel says to improve relations
we must marry french russian and israeli
women every individual has a role in
nation playing you know
so um
i
you know i i'm really glad to see that
people are willing to to put nation
above self
and
and uh to to
to play their own
uh to to play a role in in geopolitics
in an individual manner i'm glad to see
that people
are willing to stand up and and take
some responsibility for the advancement
of the nation
and and make this great sacrifice of
marrying a foreigner for the good for
the good of the country so i'm glad to
see that i'm
um
it's a good thing yes i i wish you
marshall all the best so if there are
any any eligible young ladies from these
nations france russia israel etc who are
watching
uh
please note that uh this young man
hershel is
is willing to marry one of you so go
ahead let's do some matchmaking
all right
okay so that brings me to the end of
today's questions let us take a few
questions
from the live chat if there are any
you have questions ask me a few right
now
ask me interesting questions please
all right i will take a few for a few
minutes
why does our national anthem have sinned
in it which is in pakistan should we
remove it
and we should require sindh when the
time is right
when the time is right what is next
is being neutral beneficial for india
now
india is not neutral
india is on the side
of india
and whoever else is willing
to
help us acquire
uh help us further our national interest
india is not neutral india is not
non-aligned
today's journalists and news readers etc
they will try and portray india as
non-aligned even today that is a lie
india is not non-aligned india is
multi-aligned and india's alignment is
towards its own national interest
so whoever is going to help us
achieve our long-term objectives we're
going to go along with them so india is
by no means
neutral
okay what else do we have um
do we have any other interesting
questions
is it okay for india to still be in the
commonwealth
yeah we have this sporting event that's
going on right now the commonwealth
games
you know so what is the commonwealth it
is a group of losers
a bunch of nations that were once ruled
by the british
that is the commonwealth the so-called
common wealth of nations but the thing
is that even the u.s was ruled by the
british the us
is not a member of the commonwealth they
don't they have not they are not
interested in being
a member of this club of losers
so india is still part of this
commonwealth it is a legacy of the
neheruvian era
mr nero was very much fond of
of all these things yeah
so it is a legacy of that era now today
maybe it's it is beneficial in some ways
to be part of this grouping of nations
and maybe we can use it
for benefit
so so maybe that's why we are still part
of it eventually when the times that we
may remove ourselves from the from this
grouping
so i think right now it doesn't make
much of a difference whether we are part
of it or not as long as we have our own
independent foreign policy as long as we
rise above the other nations and we
leave britain behind the dust yeah you
do that it's fine
all right all right all right do you
have any question
other questions my parents want me to
become a chartered accountant but after
watching your videos i found my interest
in physics and mathematics should i
follow my dream or should i first become
financially independent
we
one must be practical in life
yeah i don't know at what stage in your
studies you are
most likely already
been preparing at
some level for becoming a ca
the most important thing in life is to
be practical
first become financially independent
then pursue your other dreams that is
the the advice i would give to everybody
never ever be idealistic
if you are financially independent then
nobody can control you
so once you achieve that you have all
the time in the world let's say you
become financially independent at the
age of 25 30 you have 70 years left
after that
follow your dreams after that
so always be practical always achieve
financial independence
so that no one can control you
even your nearer and dear ones may want
to control you in some way or the other
you know that's how life works
so become financially independent and
then for pursue your dreams if you want
to that is the generic advice i would
give to everybody
all right um
do we have other questions that i
have not taken before
my own joy manipur annexation and
coercive merger agreement
it is quite
possible
that
see
mr patel
sardar patel
he took it upon himself to unify the
nation after uh
the so-called independence of india so
when india became independence india was
just a bunch of princely states all the
puppet regimes that the british had
installed in various parts of india
in manipur you had one such puppet
regime in 1891 the british annexed
manipur after defeating the manipuri uh
army in war they hanged the crown prince
and the
the
the number one general in manipur and
they installed a puppet government and a
puppet king who was tangentially related
to the royal dynasty of manipur and if
you look at the royal family of manipur
today which still exists they are a
descendant they are descendants of this
puppet king not the true king of manipur
yeah
so
when mr patel went about the nation
uh
persuading the various princely states
to become part of the union of india
there have there are most likely
instances in which he had to use certain
tactics
maybe
he coerced
some of them
so mr patel had the full might of the
indian state at his disposal
he had the might of the indian armed
forces at his disposal so it so these
princely states they had essentially no
option
but to sign on the dotted line
if
and if they would not do it there would
be consequences
so possibly some of them would have had
a gun pointed at their head that's
possible it's possible
and mr patel did that for the benefit of
the nation to reunify the nation
for the benefit of mr nehru and and
overall long-term interests of india so
it is alleged
that this sort of thing happened in
manipur that the king of manipur the
puppet king of manipur was forced to
sign the accession document to india it
is possible
we don't have evidence for or against
but many people have made this claim do
i know what happened i don't know what
happened is it possible that the king
was forced to sign that against his will
it is possible
that's just how life works imagine if
manipur had become independent what
would have happened
it would have anyway been dependent on
on india because it's a landlocked place
uh we know what happened subsequently
the entire far east of indian authors of
india was neglected
marginalized
there was no development there was there
was so much insurgency drug abuse all
that we know we know what the nairobi
regime and subsequent regimes did
now things are different and i'm glad to
see that
and so so yeah
so it's possible that
some such thing may have happened but
that is how the world works
we have to make the best of where we are
okay do we have any other
questions that i could
take
um
okay i think i think we're done for
today we have crossed the two-hour mark
so we're gonna call it a day here
all of you
once again thank you very much for all
the questions always always fun to
answer your questions
and let us keep doing this all right so
i will see you in the next episode next
week until that time take care keep
asking questions and i will see you soon
take care
good night good day bye